Chukwuma Okere

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

Dedicated, efficient, and passionate full stack engineer with over 7 years of experience in desktop, web and mobile development. Works with modern Front-end and Back-end technologies. Throughout my career I've built applications ranging from internal tools like Inventory Management software and company dashboards, B2B applications, custom CRMs to manage work orders and contract workers, to customer-facing games and applications like e-commerce websites/portals that handle hundreds of thousands of products and customers over various devices and platforms.

chukwumaokere@yahoo.com 1 (773) 307-2548 Chicago, IL

<u>LinkedIn</u> Github

Portfolio Site

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pixel by Pixel Studios

Senior Software Engineer - Contract

Toronto, ON, Canada (Remote) | March 2023 - June 2023

- Re-architecting a single page web app into a multi page web app, adding Web3 functionality and supporting an increase in yearly revenue by \$200k
- Migrating existing website and products to serverless architecture saving the company over \$1000/year in development and server costs
- Building RESTful APIs and RPC functions that serve data to the JavaScript front-end based on dynamically chosen user inputs that handled over 175,000 concurrent users
- Building full-stack Web3 e-commerce application to support Marbles on Stream using modern web stack comprising of React.js 18+, Node, NextJS 13, PlanetScale, Edge API Functions, Supabase, Vercel, Upstash, Sentry and Railway on ETH and SOL Blockchains

Bayfront Media

Frontend Engineer / UI/UX Designer - Contract

Sarasota, FL (Remote) | Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

- Created designs in Figma for websites and met with clients for approval
- Wrote and iterated on custom design system and custom components to increase development efficiency by 40%
- Created pixel perfect websites using custom design system and custom components

Captain.tv

Senior Software Engineer (Full-Stack)

San Francisco, CA (Remote) | Mar 2021 - April 2023

- Produced architecture design and documentation on Atlassian (Confluence) Software for 10+ products, ensuring high-quality deliverables and maintainability
- Created and maintained a digital game platform, collaborating with engineers to build features and increase user engagement (Captain.tv Hub).
- Educated and enforced modern coding standards for JavaScript/TypeScript (ES5, ES6, ESNext) and formalized them using by creating an internal tool, ensuring code quality and consistency.

SKILLS

- Modern JavaScript Frontend Frameworks (Vue, React, Angular)
- Modern JavaScript Backend Frameworks (ExpressJS, Node.js)
- JavaScript (7 years)
- Java (4 years)
- C++ (5 years)
- C# (2 years)
- .NET (2 years)
- TypeScript (5 years)
- TailwindCSS (4 years)
- Node.js (6 years)
- Figma (4 years)
- Adobe XD (4 years)
- React / React Native (6 years)
- Angular / AngularJS (5 years)
- Vue (4 years)
- Ionic Framework (4 years)
- AWS (4 years)
- Digital Ocean (6 years)
- Google Cloud Platform (3 years)
- Software Development Life Cycle (6 years)
- Application Development (6 years)
- API development/Integration (6 years)
- Express.js (6 years)
- PHP (7 years)
- MySQL (7 years)
- MongoDB (5 years)
- HTML / HTML5 (7 years)

- Built and maintained an internal npm module server on GitHub for company tools/components, reducing development time by 50% and improving developer experience.
- Used GitHub and various CI/CD (Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Terraform) to ensure smooth feature deployment
- Architected infrastructure for all web-related products using AWS tools like DynamoDB, Lambda functions, S3 buckets, BeanStalk, Route 53, CloudFront, RDS, and CloudFlare, ensuring scalability and reliability.
- Built and maintained scalable C# .NET 5/6 and NodeJS RESTful API backends and pub/sub (websocket) systems for applications/games requiring 100,000+ concurrent connections on AWS, ensuring highperformance and reliability.
- Developed large-scale e-commerce platform (100s transactions per minute) using Stripe API, PayPal API serving over 10,000+ users, enabling end-user revenue sharing and increasing company revenue by 40%.
- Led initiative to consolidate company's brand presence across all
 products by creating a design system and component library, promoting
 consistency, attractiveness, and cohesiveness in all company's products
 increasing customer retention by 30%.

Boru, Inc

Tech Consultant (Mobile App Development) - **Contract** Chicago, IL | Mar 2021 - Dec 2022

- Managed mobile app development team of 5 individuals in Agile development methodology using Ionic Framework (React)
- Maintained and updated Apple and Android developer certificates for app store deployments and OTA (over-the-air) app updates
- Handled DevOps procedures for iOS App Store and Android App Store deployments for 1000s of app users

Boru, Inc

Senior Engineer (Full-Stack) / Lead Mobile App Developer Chicago, IL | Feb 2016 - Mar 2021

- Managed and mentored a team of 5 developers to deliver web and mobile applications within budget and ahead of schedule by researching modern design solutions and understanding client requirements.
- Spearheaded the company's transition from building PHP web applications to modern JavaScript frameworks (ES5, ES6), resulting in a 20% increase in sales and 40% increase in client budget.
- Architected and optimized RESTful APIs using various backend technologies like ExpressJS, PHP, Axios and Node.js to increase software performance
- Improved front-end and back-end code to increase application performance and decrease time to process requests to increase performance in software with challenging and large datasets resulting in a decrease in client complaints by 20%.
- Developed internal tooling and reusable app templates using modern frameworks like React-Native, React, Vue, and Angular, driving down the cost of development and increasing sales by 30%.
- Worked with the CTO to modernize the company's development infrastructure with Agile methodologies and responsibilities, leading to a 30% increase in company revenue year after year and funding company bonuses.

- CSS (7 years)
- Bootstrap (6 years)
- REST (6 years)
- iOS Development (4 years)
- Android Development (4 years)
- Git (7 years)
- GitHub (7 years)
- BitBucket (5 years)
- Atlassian (Jira, Confluence)
- User Experience Design (4 years)
- User Interface Design (4 years)
- Agile Software Development (6 years)
- Redis (4 years)
- Docker (3 years)
- GraphQL (3 years)
- Microsoft SQL Server (5 years)
- Testing (4 years) (Jest, Mocha, Vitest, Cypress.io)
- UNIX based systems (Linux, RedHat, CentOS, Ubuntu) (7 years)
- Twilio, Ring Central (4 years)
- Authorize.Net (5 years)
- High attention to detail
- Excellent Teamwork and Collaboration skills
- Creative problem solving skills
- Emphasis on increased productivity through improving developer experience and increasing non-technical employees ability to contribute

EDUCATION

Some college Biology/Pre-medicine

Saint Xavier University 2012 - 2016 Chicago, IL

PROJECTS

Chess On Stream (Chat Plays Chess)

Game Designer / Software Engineer / Founder

January 2021 - March 2023

- Created and developed Chat Plays Chess and sold to Captain.tv to add to games database, consequently joined the Captain.tv team as part of the IP acquisition and went on to lead the company's JavaScript/Web development department
- Authenticated users using OAuth protocols and securely stored user access tokens and automatically refreshed and served new tokens
- Planned wrote and debugged web application (Chess Game) and software architecture using real-time communications (WebSockets) with high reliability and high throughput (Over 50,000 concurrent connections and 100,000 messages)

Socialites (Digital Agency)

Founder / Educator / Consultant

March 2018 - current

- Provides engineering, tech consultancy, and design talent to businesses wanting to level up their reach and potential
- Built Socialites School website using Vue 3, Bulma CSS, HTML5, Node.js and Express (MEVN Stack)
- Taught 10+ students and continues to educate in Front-end JavaScript technologies, Back-end Technologies, UI/UX design, and emerging web technologies/frameworks